<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/XLAB/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/XLAB/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-21T06:09:17+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/feed.xml</id><title type="html">XLAB</title><entry><title type="html">First-Year Scholars Shine: Insights into DNA Repair Mechanisms Presented at Fall Symposium 2023</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First-Year Scholars Shine: Insights into DNA Repair Mechanisms Presented at Fall Symposium 2023" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-4.html"><![CDATA[<center>
    <img src="/images/post/11_21_24.jpeg" alt="Fall Symposium 2023" width="500" />
    <figcaption>Fall Symposium 2023</figcaption>
    <h2> </h2>
</center>

<p>Johaan Kathilankal Jis, Toni Kamau, and Kareigh Gammon, who are first-years scholars in our XLab AI Biotech had the opportunity to present their research at Fall Symposium 2023 hosted by Kennesaw State University at Kennesaw, GA. Their research focused on DNA repair mechanisms, specifically the Base Excision Repair (BER) pathway which was studied by observing the Uracil-DNA glycosylase (UDG) interactions with AP: A and AP:G containing DNA. Their findings provided valuable insights about the impact of DNA interaction and binding process, contributing the field of cellular science and lung cancer research.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fall Symposium 2023]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bon Varlet Named Among Inaugural VICEROY Scholars to Advance Cyber and Spectrum Workforce for National Security</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bon Varlet Named Among Inaugural VICEROY Scholars to Advance Cyber and Spectrum Workforce for National Security" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-5.html"><![CDATA[<center>
    <img src="/images/post/11_21_24_2.png" alt="Bon Varlet" width="250" />
    <figcaption>Bon Varlet</figcaption>
    <h2> </h2>
</center>

<p>Bon Varlet was selected to become one of the 1st VICEROY scholars. VICEROY is a program created by the DoD to help build a skilled, diverse cyber and spectrum workforce through collaborate with select universities. With a focus on providing leadership opportunities and skills to students, VICEROY hopes to meet the demands of national security roles.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bon Varlet]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Johaan Kathilankal Jis Debuts Alzheimer’s Research Database at Georgia Undergraduate Research Conference 2024</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Johaan Kathilankal Jis Debuts Alzheimer’s Research Database at Georgia Undergraduate Research Conference 2024" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-6</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-6.html"><![CDATA[<center>
    <img src="/images/post/11_21_24_3.jpeg" alt="Johaan" width="400" />
    <figcaption>Johaan Kathilankal Jis</figcaption>
    <h2> </h2>
</center>

<p>Johaan Kathilankal Jis, a research assistant at X Lab AI Biotech, recently had the opportunity to represent his lab at the Georgia Undergraduate Research Conference 2024 hosted by Oxford College of Emory University in Oxford, Georgia. His research focused on creating an Alzheimer’s Disease database collection categorized by research domains, providing a valuable resource for researchers, doctors, and policymakers seeking insights into understanding Alzheimer’s Disease and Related dementia. As this is his first conference experience, Johaan looks forward to further contributing to Bioengineering and Biotechnology research.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Johaan Kathilankal Jis]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Presenting Cutting-Edge AI Research on Protein Binding at ICTAI 2024: A Deep Learning Approach</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Presenting Cutting-Edge AI Research on Protein Binding at ICTAI 2024: A Deep Learning Approach" /><published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-7</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/11/21/post-7.html"><![CDATA[<!-- <center>
    <img src="/images/post/11_21_24_3.jpeg" alt="Johaan" width=400/>
    <figcaption>Johaan Kathilankal Jis</figcaption>
    <h2> </h2>
</center> -->

<p>I had the incredible opportunity to present my research at the <strong>36th IEEE International Conference on Tools with Artificial Intelligence (ICTAI 2024)</strong>! <br />
Presentation Title: “Predicting Protein-Protein Binding Affinity with Deep Learning: A Comparative Analysis of CNN and Transformer Models” <br />
It was an honor to share my findings with such a distinguished audience and engage in meaningful discussions about the future of AI and its applications in many diverse fields. <br />
The experience of presenting at ICTAI 2024 was both rewarding and inspiring, and I’m deeply grateful for the feedback and insights from attendees. A heartfelt thank you to my advisor, collaborators, and everyone who supported this journey.</p>

<p>Looking forward to applying the feedback I received and pushing this research further!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lingtao Chen</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Spotlight on Toni Kamau: Pioneering the Future of DNA Research</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Spotlight on Toni Kamau: Pioneering the Future of DNA Research" /><published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-2.html"><![CDATA[<center>
    <img src="/images/post/toni_pos2.jpg" alt="Toni Kamau" width="500" />
    <figcaption>Toni Kamau</figcaption>
    <h2> </h2>
</center>

<p>Toni Kamau is an outstanding student researcher here at X-lab who is making waves in the field of DNA research with a unique blend of determination, innovation, and passion. Kamau was recently interviewed by Kennesaw State University where she shared her journey, challenges, and the motivating factors behind her work.</p>

<p>Kamau’s research focuses on DNA and its relation to many common diseases. She touches on the fact that DNA holds potential for transforming our understanding of enzyme repair and its applications in various fields. Her dedication to exploring the depths of DNA research is not only paving the way for scientific advancements but also serves as a beacon of hope for aspiring student researchers.</p>

<p>In the interview, Kamau discusses her background, and how she balances the rigorous demands of academia with her future goals. It’s a must-read for anyone interested in the future of science and the stories of those who are shaping it.</p>

<p>Read the full interview here: <a href="https://www.kennesaw.edu/news/stories/2024/student-finds-motivation-in-promise-of-dna-research.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.kennesaw.edu/news/stories/2024/student-finds-motivation-in-promise-of-dna-research.php</a></p>

<p>Let’s support and celebrate the remarkable contributions of emerging talents like Toni Kamau, who are pushing the boundaries of what’s possible in DNA research.</p>]]></content><author><name>Bon Varlet</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Toni Kamau]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring the Interactions Between SARS-CoV-2 Variants and hACE2 Enzyme: A Deeper Look into Our Latest Research</title><link href="/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring the Interactions Between SARS-CoV-2 Variants and hACE2 Enzyme: A Deeper Look into Our Latest Research" /><published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2024/08/08/post-3.html"><![CDATA[<h2>Introduction</h2>

<p>X-Lab is proud to announce the publication of our latest research paper in the International Journal of Molecular Sciences, titled “A Comparative Analysis of SARS-CoV-2 Variants of Concern (VOC) Spike Proteins Interacting with hACE2 Enzyme.” This study represents a significant step forward in understanding the molecular dynamics of the SARS-CoV-2 virus and its interactions with human cells.</p>

<h2>Background of the Study</h2>

<p>The COVID-19 pandemic, caused by the SARS-CoV-2 virus, has dramatically affected global health and society. As the virus has evolved, different variants of concern (VOCs) have emerged, each with mutations in the spike protein—a key component that the virus uses to enter human cells. These mutations can affect the virus’s transmissibility, vaccine effectiveness, and the severity of the disease. Our research focused on these variants and their interactions with the human angiotensin-converting enzyme 2 (hACE2), the primary receptor that the virus binds to on human cells.</p>

<h2>Key Findings</h2>

<p>The study revealed significant differences in how the spike proteins of various VOCs interact with hACE2. These differences and are driven by specific mutations that alter the spike protein’s binding interface, potentially making certain variants more efficient at entering human cells. These findings contribute to our understanding of why certain variants spread more rapidly and may also provide insights into how to design more effective vaccines and therapeutics that target these variants. Our study also highlights regions of the spike protein that remain conserved across variants, suggesting potential targets for broad-spectrum vaccines and treatments.</p>

<p>For more detail, please read out full publication <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/382556876_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_SARS-CoV-2_Variants_of_Concern_VOC_Spike_Proteins_Interacting_with_hACE2_Enzyme" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/382556876_A_Comparative_Analysis_of_SARS-CoV-2_Variants_of_Concern_VOC_Spike_Proteins_Interacting_with_hACE2_Enzyme</a></p>]]></content><author><name>Bon Varlet</name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introduction]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain</title><link href="/XLAB/2023/11/03/post-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain" /><published>2023-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-21T06:07:21+00:00</updated><id>/XLAB/2023/11/03/post-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/XLAB/2023/11/03/post-1.html"><![CDATA[<h2>Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain</h2>
<p>Nov 3, 2023 Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain National Battlefield Park</p>

<center>
<img src="/images/post/11_03_23_1.jpeg" alt="group" width="600" />

<img src="/images/post/11_03_23_2.jpeg" alt="group" width="600" />
</center>]]></content><author><name>Jay Chen</name></author><category term="Group" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain Nov 3, 2023 Group Hiking at Kennesaw Mountain National Battlefield Park]]></summary></entry></feed>